本字幕由人人影视字幕组翻译
禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
翻译   kiko   S很爱笑   CS小明漫画家    我叫魏碧慧   小奶
翻译   蔡茸茸   Marshal同学   天启章鱼X    lottie筱妤
时间轴   太太乐叽叽    安妮    sumen     后期   小亲斤
校对   米小勒       总监   米小勒
僵 尸
国 度
.
第一季 第九集
宝贝过来这里
Come here baby.
《僵尸国度》前情提要
Previously on Z Nation.
各位晚上好  我叫它僵尸重击
Good night, everyone! I call it the Z Whacker.
听着  我就是不相信摩菲
Look, I just don't trust Murphy, okay?
那家伙肯定有古怪
There's something wrong with that dude.
万一这是真的呢
What if it's true?
万一摩菲真如他们所说的那样
What if Murphy's who they say he is
万一我们真有机会制造出疫苗呢
and there's a chance for a vaccine?
因为那是个希望  麦克
Cuz that's hope, Mack.
那不是希望  那是谎话
It's not hope. It's a lie,
这谎话会害死我们的
and it's gonna get us both killed.
那我也情愿因相信这个谎话而死
Well then I'd rather die believing in a lie
总好过没有信仰地苟且活着
than live believing in nothing.
高速公路162  四角保护区  犹他州
我累到可以一觉长眠不起
I'm so tired I could sleep for a thousand years.
我们就在这里扎营吧
Let's just camp here, yeah?
我们该走了
We should get moving.
为什么不能待在这里呢
Why can't we stay here?
我们已经超过约定时间两天  可能是三天了
We're probably two days out from the rendezvous. Maybe three.
这或许是我们赶上其他小伙伴最后的机会了
This may be our last chance to sync up with the others.
我希望市民Z这回没搞错
Yeah well I hope Z gets it right this time.
我们去了
Well we went
南部
south.
他们去了西部
They went west.
我们很可能会在中部碰面
Hopefully we'll hook up somewhere in the middle.
我们得转去西部才行
We got to angle west.
是西部没错  加利福尼亚就在那个方向
West is that way. California's that way.
要是它还存在的话
If it's still there.
要是我们能找到通讯设备
Well if we can power up somewhere
我就能和市民Z联系上了
I can try to get in touch with Z.
没准还能获知他们的最新位置
See if maybe I can get an update on their location.
我有点嫉妒那家伙了
I sorta envy that dude.
离这喧嚣尘世远远的
So far away from all this.
没错  可他孤身一人
Yeah, and all alone.
我们朝西部出发
We're gonna go west.
我们去和大队会合
We're gonna meet up with the team.
送摩菲到实验室去
We're gonna get Murphy to that lab,
然后找到治愈僵尸病毒的方法
and then we are going to cure this virus.
真是任重而道远
That's a lot of stuff we're doing.
说的没错
It sure is.
还有那些不在任务之列的事情呢
What about some of the things we aren't doing?
你指什么
What do you mean?
比如讨论一下  前戏神马的
Like talking, for starters.
最近你甚至都不正眼看我了呢
Lately it seems like you can't even look at me.
就像现在这样
Like right now.
艾迪
Addy,
发生什么了
what's going on?
我跟你说过了麦克  我正在努力排解好吗
I told you, Mack. I'm working through it, okay?
我只是不确定
It's a big knot that
现在该不该解开这个心结
I'm just not sure I want to untie right now.
不是一切问题都和你有关
Not everything is about you.
这里风景真好  我们就不能待在这里吗
It's really beautiful. Can we just stay here please?
美景会引来麻烦
Beauty attracts trouble.
你应该知道的
You should know that.
好的
Okay.
我们应该待在那条小溪边上
We should've stayed at the...at the creek.
我以为这点汽油能多撑会  都怪我行吧
Thought we'd get farther on the gas. That's on me. All right?
艾迪  你在看什么
Addy, what are you looking at?
你还好吗
You okay?
艾迪
Addy?
你没事吧
You okay?
什么
What?
感觉你好像去过某个地方
It's like you go somewhere.
你到底看到了什么
I mean what is it you see exactly?
麦克  我累了  不想聊这个
Mack, I'm too tired for this.
艾迪
Addy.
麦克
Mack.
你总是这样精神恍惚的  我们得谈谈
We need to talk about when you drift off like this.
很显然  有什么事情在折磨你
I mean obviously something is tearing you up.
只有真正了解你的困扰  我才能帮助你
I might be able to help if I knew what you were dealing with,
但你一直把我拒之门外
but you keep shutting me out.
好吧
Okay.
我想应该是段回忆吧
It's a memory, I think.
我不知道是什么触发了它
I don't know what triggers it,
但无论何时  就好像...
but whenever it happens it's like...
我到了一个自己曾去过的地方
it's like I go somewhere where I've been.
当我试着回忆时
And when I try to remember, it just
这种感觉变得愈发虚无缥缈
it gets further and further away.
你看到了什么
What do you see?
都是同一件事  不断重复上演
It's the same thing. It's over and over again.
周围一片漆黑
It's dark.
然后  好像有一盏灯
There's...there's like a light.
还有一个僵尸
And then a Z.
一个非常凶恶的僵尸
Like a really bad one.
然后就是一场恶战
And it's fighting.
谁和僵尸的恶战
Who's it fighting?
我不知道
I don't know.
可能是你
Maybe you.
我
Me, huh?
是的  我一直想不清楚这个部分
Yeah, I can never make that part out. But
但是这僵尸肯定没死
the Z will not die.
能不能...  抱歉  我们能聊点别的吗
Can we...I'm sorry, can we talk about something else?
就这样
Okay.
当然可以  宝贝
Sure, babe.
你想聊点什么呢
What would you like to talk about?
不聊我了  那就聊聊你吧
We're not talking about me. Talk about you.
估计很快就没的聊了
This is probably gonna be a short conversation.
我会一直向你发问
I'll keep it going with questions.
好吧  你打算...
Ummm, okay. What...
如果可以  你现在最想做什么
If you could do anything, what would you do right now?
除了那破裤裆的事儿  你最想做什么
Besides the obvious. What would you do?
我告诉你我想做什么
I'll tell you exactly what I would do.
我会
I would
带你
take you out
去一个很棒的餐厅
to a great restaurant.
城里最好的
The best in town.
穿戴整齐
I mean dress up.
冲个澡
Shower.
全套的  全套的
Whole package, the whole deal.
我会为你开门  帮你摆好椅子
I would open the doors for you. I would pull out your chair.
我们点些酒
We'd order some wine.
美美地吃一顿
Have a great meal.
然后再点些酒
Order some more wine.
之后我会
And then I would just...
盯着你美丽的眼睛  看一整晚
I would just stare into your beautiful eyes all night
听你讲自己的事
and listen to you talk about yourself.
然后我们回到美妙之极的公寓  嘿嘿...
Then we'd go back to our fabulous pad and...
我们没戏的  麦克
We never stood a chance, Mack.
等等
Hold on.
你说什么
What are you saying to me?
想想吧
Think about it, like
你我的关系  是以什么为基础的
our relationship. What's it based on?
我们有什么共同点吗
Do we even have anything in common?
我们都活着
We're alive.
活着这个动因还不行吗
How's that for starters?
是啊  我就是说这个
Yeah, but that's about it.
灾难爆发的第一天晚上我们相遇了
We met on the first night of the outbreak.
我们甚至不了解对方
We don't even know each other.
我们知道的就是僵尸和骚乱
All we know is zombies and mayhem.
艾迪  我们互相支持着活下来
Addy, we've kept each other alive.
我是说  不管情况有多糟
I mean no matter how bad it's gotten,
我们都不离不弃
we've been there for each other.
这比结婚戒指带来的羁绊更加深刻
That's so much more of a bond than any ring could give us.
是的  但是...
Yeah, but...
我们之间是痛苦的羁绊
we're trauma bonded.
我们一起杀戮
We kill together,
我们一起活了下来
we survive together, and
还一起滚了床单
we have sex together.
但就是这些  这就是一切了
But that's it. That's all we have.
没错  我们在灾难的第一天就相遇了
Yeah, we met on night one.
可我甚至记不清那晚了
And I don't even remember that night really. Like
对我来说那晚就是模糊的...
for me it's just one blur of...
好吧
Okay.
混乱
Madness.
是的  没错  我是说
Yeah, yeah. I mean
那很糟糕  并且
that was bad, and and
并且在此之前  我们遇到了很多
we got a lot of bad shit to go through
糟糕的情况  可是艾迪
before this is all over. But Addy,
我需要你  可我不懂你的意思  我们...
I need you. I don't know what you're talking about, we...
你说我们没戏  这是什么意思
we never had a chance. What do you mean by that?
我是说  宝贝  过去三年里
I mean, babe, in three years
我们从没想到过明天过后的事情
we have never thought about anything past tomorrow.
直到...
You know until this
有了这项疯狂的任务  这项...
crazy mission came about, which you know is
就我们而言应该肩负的任务
probably done as far as we're concerned.
但这也不意味着我们玩完了好吗
That doesn't mean we're done.
我们现在在自己骗自己好吗...
Yeah, but who are we kidding? What...
我和你会有一个怎样的未来呢
what kind of future do you and I have?
我们会做些什么
What are we gonna do?
我们会结婚生子吗
We gonna get married? Have some kids?
那种事你想都不能想
You can't even think about that stuff.
那很疯狂  是不可能的事
It's crazy. It's impossible.
我们有彼此啊
We have each other.
我们从未约会过
We've never been on a date.
少来
No?
我不会让那成为我们的羁绊
That's not gonna cut it.
好吧
Okay.
别这样
Stop.
艾迪生
Addison.
你有中间名吗
Do you have a middle name?
恩  我有
Yeah, I got a middle name.
是什么
What is it?
格雷斯[意为优雅]
It's Grace.
很适合你
Of course it is.
艾迪生·格雷斯·卡弗  你愿意和我出去
Addison Grace Carver, will you go out with me?
约会吗
On a date?
-麦克  -我保证不会是打打杀杀了
- Mack. - I promise we won't kill a thing.
好了  嘘  你...
Okay. Shhh. You know what...
你就在这漂漂亮亮的待着  哪也别去
You just sit here and look pretty. Don't go anywhere.
我还能去哪
Where am I gonna go?
好了  艾迪  不是想要约会吗
All right, Addy. You wanted a date?
我们的第一次约会来了
Here is our first date.
不是吧
No.
艾迪
Addy?
好吧  没关系  你继续睡吧
All right, that's fine. You go ahead and get your sleep.
末世漫漫无绝期啊
It's been a long apocalypse.
麦克
Mack!
艾迪
Addy?
麦克
Mack!
艾迪
Addy?
艾迪  你在里面吗
Addy, you in here?
艾迪
Addy?
搞什么鬼
What the hell?
这些是咬痕吗
Are those bites?
什么东西会咬僵尸呢
What bites a zombie?
艾迪
Addy.
Addy?
告诉我你是打了这混蛋后逃走了
Please tell me you did a hit and run on this bastard!
混蛋
Damn, dude.
该死的巨人安德雷[著名摔跤手]  艾迪
Freaking Andre the Giant. Addy!
好吧
All right.
宝贝  不要啊
Baby, no.
你从哪得到这串项链的
Where'd you get that necklace?
这项链是从哪儿弄来的  尼玛
Where did you get that necklace? Huh?
回答我  你个无脑变态
Answer me, you brain dead freak!
哦  宝贝
Oh, baby.
好了
Okay.
没事了  没事的
You're fine. You're fine.
麦克！
Mack!
艾迪?
Addy?
艾迪  你去哪儿了
Addy? Where'd you go?
等等
Oh, wait a minute.
搞毛线
What?
我曾到过这儿
I've been here.
好吧
Right.
哈哈  咬我啊
Ha. Bite me.
这并不代表她死了  麦克
Doesn't mean she's dead, Mack.
很可能她拼尽全力给它一棒后就脱身了
She could've given it her best shot then bolted.
她是个聪明的姑娘
She's a smart girl.
站住  丑男
Hey, ugly!
艾迪
Addy.
你要吃谁脑子都行
You can have all the others!
就是不能伤害艾迪
You cannot have her!
她不能死
She didn't deserve this.
此一时彼一时哦
Sometimes you're the windshield. Sometimes you're the bug.
这是她的项链
This is her necklace.
不能给你
You can't have it.
绝不对你留情
No mercy.
有没有搞错
Come on.
你打了兴奋剂吗
You on steroids?! Huh?!
我生来就喜欢堂堂正正地跟人干架
I was brought up to compete clean.
向右多跳一步就好了  麦克
One foot to the right, Mack.
走开
Go away.
这一轮我就快死了
I'll be dead soon.
重生模式倒计时
Not soon enough.
艾迪
Addy?
麦克
Mack!
该死
Damn it.
这一轮向右跳
To the right.
向右跳  向右跳  麦克
To the right! To the right, Mack!
尼玛  跳太远了
Too far.
大哥  您又来
You again?
麦克
Mack!
我记得这扇门
I know that door.
我在哪见过这扇门
Where have I seen that door before?
怎么回事
What is it, huh?!
你到底要对我做什么
What do you want from me?!
怎么回事
What is it, huh?!
你到底要干什么
What do you want from me?!
回答我!
Answer me!
是艾迪吗
What is it Addy?!
你休想打她主意
You can't have her.
我不会让你得逞的
I won't let you.
门后面有什么东西
Is there something behind that door
是你不想让我看到的吗
you don't want me to see?
就是因为这个吗
Is that what this is?
到底是什么
What is it?
为什么  伙计  是艾迪吗
What is it, man? Is it Addy?
你到底不想让我看到什么
What is it you don't want me to see?
麦克
Mack?
你还好吧
Are you okay?
还好
Yeah.
还好  就是额...
Yeah, ummm...
不太好
No.
我不知道怎么了
I don't know.
能跟我说说吗
You want to talk about it?
我做了个梦
I had this dream.
其实不像梦  更像是预兆  就好像是...
It's more like a premonition than a dream. You know it's like
通灵梦魇
a psychic nightmare.
哇哦
Whoa,
通灵
Psychic?
麦克·汤姆森  你可是世界头号怀疑论者
Mack Thompson, world's most skeptical man,
你还会有通灵预兆呢
is having psychic premonitions?
过来
Come here.
干什么呢
What are you doing?
试试你的体温
Taking your temperature.
我觉得你是发烧烧糊涂了
I think you're having a fever dream.
艾迪  别闹
Addy, come on.
我是认真的
This is serious.
我也是认真的
I'm serious too.
你别忘了  我们现在在荒无人烟的地方
Okay, if you haven't noticed, we're in the middle of nowhere.
我们没水喝  没东西吃  没汽油
We have no water. We have no food or fuel.
我不能让你在我身边倒下  亲爱的
I can't have you falling apart on me, babe.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我也不会在你身边倒下的
I'm not falling apart on you though.
不会的
I'm not.
只不过...
It's just...
那感觉太真实了  你知道吗
It just felt so real, you know?
好像梦境背后隐藏着某件事
You know it felt like it's about something, you know?
肯定是有什么事  肯定有事
It is about something. It is. It has to be.
但我觉得不是关于未来的
But I don't think it's the future.
我觉得问题在于你
I think it's about you.
一定是你的潜意识
I think your subconscious is trying to
想要告诉你某件事
tell you something.
好吗
Okay?
所以我们...我们一起来解决
So let's...let's figure it out.
发生什么了
What happened?
好吧
Okay.
我一直...一直在重复做着同一个梦
It's... It's one of these dreams that keeps repeating,
每次的梦境又有点不一样
you know like each time it's a little bit different.
每次我醒来时都在你身边
Each time I wake up next to you.
可我朝你那儿看时发现你不见了
I look over and you're gone.
然后我听到你哭喊
I hear you crying.
好吧  那没什么
Okay, well that one's easy.
你都...都不需要用佛洛依德那套
You don't... don't need Freud
或者脑部扫描就能搞明白
or a brain scan to figure that one out.
麦克  你那是在担心我
Mack, you're worried about me.
听着  我也担心你
And listen, I'm worried about you too.
但这...  这没那么简单
But that's...that's not just it.
这只是梦的开始  好吗
That's just how it starts, right?
之后我就听到你在求救
And then I hear you,
你好像遇到了什么麻烦
and you're in some kind of trouble.
再之后我就听到一个声音
And then and then I hear this sound,
好像是僵尸在远处大吼大叫
this like zombie howl echoing off in the distance.
真的是超级恐怖
It's super creepy.
来了  就是这个声音
There it is. That's the sound.
又来了  那个声音
There it is again. That sound.
我告诉你  那玩意就在外面
I'm telling you, that thing is out there.
喂喂喂  一个僵尸而已
Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey. It's a zombie.
好吧  听着  你听我说
Okay so hey, hey listen.
我们去杀死它
Let's go kill it,
一起去
together.
好吗
Okay?
看  快看  快看
Watch, watch, watch.
它马上就要出现了  就是那里
It's gonna show up right over there.
你确定吗
You sure?
马上就会出现
Any second.
麦克
Mack?
搞什么  这太奇怪了
What? That's so weird.
这...
It's...
在梦里我就站在这里
I've stood right here and
每次都能看到它
and and seen it every time in my dream.
就是这里
Right here!
麦克  听着  麦克
Mack, listen. Mack!
麦克
Mack!
这不对劲
This isn't right.
这之前是...
This was...
是这里吗
Is it here?
-退后  快退后  -好的  好的
- Stay back, stay back. - Okay, okay.
好的
Okay.
麦克  你在找什么
Mack, what are you looking for?
一条蛇
A snake.
就是这里
It's here.
它...  它总是...  总是在这里出现
It's...it's...it's always right here.
你觉得我疯了  是吗
You think I'm crazy, don't you?
没有
No.
也许是有一点
Maybe a little bit.
但是麦克  听着  听我说
But Mack, hey listen, listen.
我们就生活在这个世界里
It's the world we're living in.
多多少少都有点精分
Okay, we're all a little bit crazy.
有些不对劲
Something's not right.
麦克  等等
Mack! Wait!
-麦克  -子弹上膛吧
- Mack! - Lock and load.
它可不好对付  2米左右  250多斤
This thing is badass. 6'7", maybe 280.
当你听到老鹰叫  你就赶快到我身边来
And when you hear a hawk, you stand right next to me
那意味着诡异的事情就要发生了
because all hell's about to break loose.
发生了什么
What's happening?
这里就是它上次杀死我的地方
This is where it killed me the last time.
听起来真恐怖
Sounds horrible.
还好只是个梦
I'm glad that was just a dream.
麦克  这是...
Hey Mack, is that...
这是你梦到的那扇门吗
is that the door from your dream?
对  就是它
Yeah, that's it.
也许我们该瞧瞧里面都有什么
Maybe we should go see what's inside.
我觉得这样不妥
I don't think that's a good idea.
你在梦里有进去过吗
In your dream, did you ever go inside?
没  每次我还没到那就被僵尸怪干掉了
No, Frankenzombie always killed me before I made it that far.
我们应该进去看看
Yeah, we should see.
别去了
No.
算了吧  万一我们还是身处梦境的轮回之中呢
No, come on. What if this is just a dream again?
万一那个怪物在那儿等着我们去送死呢
I mean what if that thing is just waiting in there to kill us?
麦克  我们不可能在同一个梦境里  好吗
Mack, we can't both be having the same dream, okay?
因为我的意识很清醒
Because I'm awake.
艾迪
Addy.
你确定你想这么做吗
You sure you want to do this?
对啊  我们大老远跑过来的
Yeah, we've come this far.
难道你不好奇里面是什么吗
Don't you want to know what's inside?
不好奇  因为肯定不是什么好东西
No. Whatever it is, it's bad.
所以我们还是赶快走吧
So let's just...let's just get out of here.
麦克  那只是个恶梦而已
Mack, it was a nightmare.
也许这里面没什么可怕的
There's probably nothing bad in there.
但此时若不一探究竟  就永远无法得知了
But if we don't look, we'll never know.
艾迪  不要
Addy, no.
好吧
Okay.
好了  谜团揭开  世界美妙了
Okay, great, mystery solved. I feel so much better now.
可以走了吗
Can we go?
哥们
Dude.
怎能就此放弃呢
Can't give up yet.
好吧  行了  艾迪  让我来
Okay. All right, Addy. Come on.
你看见什么了吗
What do you see?
不清楚
I don't know.
太暗了  也许是...
It's so dark. Maybe
是个房间吧  但我也不确定
it's some kind of room, but I can't tell.
那你再加把劲儿
Okay, well keep trying.
什么也没有  我们还是走吧
There's nothing in there. Let's just go, okay?
再仔细看看
Keep trying.
有什么吗
What is it?
等一下  我的眼睛还在适应  太暗了
Hang on. My eyes are still adjusting. It's so dark in here.
伸手不见五指
It's pitch black.
看起来像个楼梯间
Looks like a staircase
通向地下室
leading down.
不要  不要
No. No.
不要怕
Don't be afraid.
别害怕
麦克
Mack!
艾迪
Addy?
不要  你弄伤我了  不要
Don't! You're hurting me! Don't!
那东西咬了我
It bit me.
你怎么还不死
Why won't you die?
你怎么还不死  你怎么还不死
Why won't you die?! Why won't you die?!
麦克  醒醒  醒醒
Mack, wake up! Wake up!
你做恶梦了  只是个恶梦而已
You're having a nightmare. Hey, you're having a nightmare, okay?
你说梦话了
You're talking in your sleep.
我说什么了
What was I saying?
你怎么还不死...  你怎么还不死
Why won't you die, why...why won't you die.
麦克
Mack?
艾迪  有些事我得告诉你
Addy, there's something I have to tell you.
和你的噩梦有关吗
Does it have to do with the dream?
到底怎么了
What is it?
艾迪  有件事我必须要问你
Addy, I have to ask you something.
你到底
Where
是从哪搞来的这个
did this come from?
姐不害怕
I am not afraid.
不要  你弄疼我了  不要
Don't! You're hurting me! Don't!
我的天
Oh my God.
怎么了这是
What happened?
麦克
Mack!
麦克  快来帮我
Mack, I need your help!
坚持住  好吗
Hang on. Okay?
我们会找到人来救你的  好吗
We're gonna get you help, okay?
麦克
Mack!
谁在那里
Somebody there?
怎么了你
What's wrong?
你被感染了吗
Are you infected?
是你伤的他吗
Did you do this to him?
你怎么还不死
Why won't you die?
这都第几遍了你还不死
你不死我都想死了
Why won't you die?
艾迪
Addy?
艾迪  你去哪了
Addy, where'd you go?
麦克
Mack!
艾迪
Addy!
艾迪宝贝  怎么了这是  怎么了
Addy, baby, baby. Baby, what's wrong? Hey, what's wrong?
麦克  太对不起了
Mack, I'm so sorry.
我还以为是你神经
I thought it was you.
这么长时间我一直以为是你神经
All this time I thought it was you.
我算知道那些闪回是怎么回事了
I know what the flashbacks were about.
我以为是你神经  其实是姐自己神经
I thought it was you, but it was me.
天啊  原来是姐  姐是深井冰啊
Oh my God, it was me. It was me.
病毒最初爆发的晚上...
That first night...
我还不知道
I didn't know.
当时我还不知道  我还不知道怎么施以仁慈
I didn't know. I didn't know how to give mercy.
我还不知道要捅大脑
I didn't know you had to kill the brain.
我就这么一刀一刀又一刀地捅她
I just kept stabbing her over and over and over again.
天啊
Oh my God.
我杀了她  麦克  天啊  原谅我吧
I killed her, Mack. Oh my God. Forgive me.
我杀了我妈妈
I killed my mom.
我杀了她
I killed her.